indiamike.com 2007-12-15

# India Travel Forum | IndiaMike.com - Privacy Policy

As a responsible website IndiaMike.com is committed to safeguarding your online privacy. Please do read the following policy to understand how your private information will be treated while you make full use of our site. This policy may change from time to time so please come back to check periodically. IndiaMike.com or its subsidiary may collect the information explained herein under.

  **1\. What identifiable information is collected from me?**

IndiaMike.com may collect information in several ways from one or different parts of website.   
IndiaMike.com may ask you for personal information at times, including, but not limited to, when you enter in a contest or promotion sponsored by IndiaMike.com and/or our other contracted partners; when you browse for travel arrangements, looking at the images on the site and when you report a problem with one of our sites or services. IndiaMike.com occasionally may also ask site user to complete surveys that are use for internal research. Wherever IndiaMike.com collects personal information an effort is made to include a link to this Privacy Policy on that page.

  **2\. What are cookies and how IndiaMike.com uses them?**

As combined part of offering and providing customized and personalized services, IndiaMike.com may use cookies to store and track your information. A cookie is a miniscule amount of data that is sent to your browser from a Web server that may be stored on your computer's hard drive.   

Generally, we use cookies to:

  *  Cache your personalized settings for items such as route language and default country location.   

  *  Determine whether you are using a public computer so that any IndiaMike.com settings changed while using a public computer do not affect the next user's ability to use IndiaMike.com   

  *  Roughly Estimate our audience or browsers. Each fresh browser trying to access IndiaMike.com may be given a cookie. That maybe used to determine the extent of repeat usage by the user.  

  *   Assist us to track the number of visits to and activities at the IndiaMike.com  

  *  Track your progress and number of entries or queries in some of our promotions, and contests. When a IndiaMike.com -hosted promotion uses cookies, the information written to the cookie may be used to track the entries, submissions made, and status in prize drawings list.   

  *  Measure certain specific traffic patterns to the site, track the areas of IndiaMike.com network of Web sites visited, track the Web site or geographical location through which you came to IndiaMike.com and your visiting patterns in average. We use this research to understand our users' visit habits and browsing preferences or if they are similar or different from one another so that we can make each visit by you on IndiaMike.com better then last one. We may use this information to better the content, banners, and promotions that you and other users will be likely to see on our sites.  

  *   IndiaMike.com also collects geophysical IP addresses for system and server administration and to report visiting information to our advertisers.   

  *  Other advertising networks that may serve advertisings onto IndiaMike.com network may also use their own cookies.   

  *  IndiaMike.com and its advertisers may also use small pieces of code called ''web beacons'' or electronic images that are sometime called "single-pixel GIF" to collect anonymous and average advertising patterns, such as counting hits, browser type, time spent viewing a page, type of page views, promotion views, or advertising responses. These "web beacons" may be used to deliver cookies that conform to our anonymous cookie policy. IndiaMike.com does not allow access or sell other advertisers or their advertising networks, information collected from you.  

**3\. Who is collecting information at IndiaMike.com?**

When you are visiting a IndiaMike.com site and are asked for personal information, you are sharing that information for use by IndiaMike.com alone, unless it is specifically stated otherwise. Some IndiaMike.com services may be offered in conjunction with a third partner. In order to provide this service to you, it may be necessary for us to share your personal information with our partner company. In such cases you will be notified prior to the time of the data collection or transfer. Where as if you do not want your data to be shared, you can choose not to allow the transfer of such data by not using that particular service at all. 

Sometime promotions that run on IndiaMike.com network sites may be sponsored by companies other than IndiaMike.com or may be co-sponsored by IndiaMike.com and another company. Some or all data collected during such a promotion may be shared with the sponsor. In the event of data being shared, you will be notified prior to the time of data collection or transfer. So you can decide whether to participate in the promotion, if you don't want your data to be shared.  Please be advised that IndiaMike.com advertisers or Web sites that have links on our site may collect personally identifiable information about you. Such information practices of those Web sites linked to IndiaMike.com are expressly not covered by this privacy statement once you leave IndiaMike.com and go over to the website of the advertiser.  

**4\. With who else IndiaMike.com will share my information?**  

As a thumb rule, IndiaMike.com will not willfully disclose any of your personally identifiable information except when we have your permission or under extraneous circumstances, such as when we believe in good faith that the law requires it or under the circumstances described below. Described herein under are some of the ways that your information may be shared or disclosed. 

Sponsors & Business Partners: IndiaMike.com may disclose your personal information to business partners or sponsors, but this is specifically and expressly described to you at the time of data collection or prior to transferring the data. Some or all data collected during a IndiaMike.com promotion may be shared with a sponsor. If a part of personally identifying data about you will be shared, we will tell you before we collect or transfer the data. 

Miscellaneous: IndiaMike.com may also disclose user information in such cases where we have reason to believe that disclosure of this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) or IndiaMike.com ’s rights or property, other IndiaMike.com users, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities. IndiaMike.com may disclose user information when we believe in good faith that the law or law-enforcing agency requires it.  

**5\. Do I have choices or controls regarding collection, use, and distribution of my identifiable information?**

By modifying your browser preferences, you have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set, or to reject all cookies. If you choose to reject all cookies you will be unable to use some of IndiaMike.com services that require the use of cookies in order to participate.  IndiaMike.com as a policy does not sell or rent your information to anyone. We will notify you at the time of data collection or transfer if your data will be shared with a third party and you will always have the option of not permitting the transfer. You can choose not to use a particular service or not to participate in certain promotions or contests, if you do not wish to allow such data sharing.  

**6\. How much protected is my personal financial information?**

To keep your personal financial information private is vital and important to us. As with all personal information, IndiaMike.com will never rent or sell your personal financial information. Your use of certain services or features, known to us, may help us to offer you better and more relevant content and advertisements. Yet as with all personally identifiable information, we do not make this available to any third parties without your permission. 

Please note that as of now IndiaMike.com do not conduct any services for which any financial dealing is required but in future there may be places on the IndiaMike.com where you can transmit credit card information in order to complete a purchase transaction or for verification purposes. Any time we ask for a credit card number we transmit that credit card number in an encrypted format. We use best industry-standard, SSL (secure socket layer) encryption technology. This sophisticated encryption process ensures that prying eyes are unable to decode your personal data when it travels from your computer to ours.  

**7\. What security precautions are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of information?  **

It may not be a norm but the fact remains that no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure always. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, IndiaMike.com cannot ensure or warrant the total security of any information you transmit to us or for our online products purchase or services, and you do so at your own risk. But once we receive your transmission, we strive and make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems. 

  **8\. What else should I know about my privacy?**

Do keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information online - for example on message boards, through email, on mailing lists or in chat areas - that information can be seen and collected and used by others. In nutshell, if you post personal information online that is accessible to the other public, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return.   
Finally, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and/or any registration information. Please be careful and responsible on your own whenever you're online. 

**  9\. Is there any children's privacy?**

Yes, the safety of children is very important to us. Children should always ask a parent for permission before sending personal information to IndiaMike.com or to anyone online for that matter. IndiaMike.com does not share personal information about users under the age of 13 with third parties under any circumstances unless there is a special situation and such information is requested by law enforcing agency and we do not sell or rent personal information about any of our users, regardless of their age. IndiaMike.com is an information site and as a policy we never display by way of direct or any third party agreement, any pornographic material. 

**  10\. Additional Information **

Any more questions or clarifications regarding this statement should be directed to [mailto@indiamike.com](mailto:mailto@indiamike.com)

Policy last updated on May 14, 2005
